nearbynow.com 2014-02-12

# Privacy Policy | JiWire

###  JiWire Advertising Privacy Policy

###  JiWire Website Privacy Policy 

####  JiWire Advertising Privacy Policy  
 **Effective Date: 09/10/12**

**Introduction**

This privacy policy applies to JiWire, Inc.’s (JiWire, we, us, our) advertising solution. This privacy policy describes how JiWire collects and uses the information we obtain from our WiFi network partners as well as our third-party mobile application partners. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your information.

JiWire is a location-based media company that provides an advertising platform and revenue model for public Wi-Fi networks and mobile applications. JiWire partners with these services to bring advertising revenue into their services, so they have additional income to provide great public Wi-Fi access and useful mobile applications for the on-the-go lifestyle.

We work only with public Wi-Fi networks that you have opted in to connect to and with mobile applications that have received your permission before your device transmits any location information.

JiWire has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/3rd-party-data-collection/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your information.  The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software.  The TRUSTe program covers only the information that is collected by JiWire through their WiFi network partners and third-party mobile application partners.

TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@jiwire.com](mailto:privacy@jiwire.com).  If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

_Laptops and mobile device on Wi-Fi_ : Every public Wi-Fi access point in the JiWire network is mapped in our system. When you connect to the hotspots, our servers know the location of the public Wi-Fi access point. In that way, we are able to serve you ads that are relevant to what is currently around you.

_Mobile device_ : If you agree to share your location when you sign into an app, that information can be shared with JiWire when an ad is shown on your screen. JiWire works only with apps that offer you the ability to opt-out of having your location data collected. 

JiWire knows you value your privacy and we pledge to protect it and adhere to industry standards for Internet and mobile advertising. We take privacy very seriously and the company does not sell, rent or share any personally identifiable information.

**Information Collection**

We use cookies and web beacons to collect information in connection with visitors to our partner Wi-Fi networks and mobile applications.

Cookies are small pieces of information stored on your device with information about your visit to a particular site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. Session ID cookies are erased when you close your browser. A persistent cookie is a small file stored on your device for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies enable us to track and target the interests of users to enhance their experience.

Web beacons are invisibly embedded electronic images and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. These technologies help us to deliver cookies, count visits, and understand usage activity of users.

We automatically collect and receive information about visitors such as, but not limited to, browser identifiers, session information, browser cookies, device type, carrier provider, IP addresses, unique device ID (such as MAC address), carrier user ID, geo-location information, sites visited and clicks on advertisements we display.

**How We Use and Disclose Information**  
JiWire uses the collected information to target and display advertisements that may be of interest to you.

We may provide the collected information to our subsidiaries, third party partners and agents to improve advertisement targeting, make and create offers, provide reporting to advertisers and clients, and to improve our systems and products.

**Opting Out**  
If you wish to not have the information we collect used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads while you access the networks of our WiFi partners, you may opt-out by [clicking here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/?type=jiwire&pid=jiwire01&aid=jiwire01&cid=jiwire&w=300&h=250).  If you wish to not have the information we collect used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads while you access the third-party applications of our mobile partners, you may opt-out by selecting the  icon within the advertisement and following the instructions.  Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising.  You will continue to receive generic ads.

If you want to completely turn off location-based services on your iPhone, iPad or Android device, see these helpful instructions at [www.jiwire.com/location-services](http://www.jiwire.com/location-services). By turning off the location-based services, you will lose all the benefits of location-based advertising on your phone.

**Security**

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the information we collect, both during transmission and once we receive it.  No method of transmission, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however.  Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**How long is the data stored?**  
JiWire retains the data it collects through its advertising solution for a period of up to 2 and a half years.  After this time the data is anonymized, aggregated and then stored for analytical purposes.

**Tracking of children**  
JiWire does not knowingly track the personally identifiable information of people under the age of 13 or knowingly track information from sites directed to people under the age of 13.

**Updates to privacy policy**  
We may change or update our privacy policy at our discretion. If we make changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you by posting a prominent announcement on our Site so that any changes are easy to find. We will obtain your consent before making any material changes to information we collect and the manner in which we use it. If we make any material changes we will notify you by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**Questions?** If you have a question or issue with the JiWire Privacy Policy please send an email to [privacy@jiwire.com](mailto:privacy@jiwire.com) or you can send us a letter to: JiWire Inc., Attn: Privacy Policy Manager, 150 Post Street, Suite 500, San Francisco, CA, 94108.

####  JiWire Website Privacy Policy  
 **Effective Date: 03/30/12**

**Introduction**  
This privacy statement applies to [www.jiwire.com](http://www.jiwire.com/) owned and operated by JiWire, Inc. (JiWire, we, us, our). This privacy statement describes how JiWire collects and uses the personal information you provide on our web site: [www.jiwire.com](http://www.jiwire.com/). It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

JiWire is a location-based media company that provides an advertising platform and revenue model for public Wi-Fi networks and mobile applications. JiWire partners with these services to bring advertising revenue into their services, so they have additional income to provide great public Wi-Fi access and useful mobile applications for the on-the-go lifestyle.

We work only with public Wi-Fi networks that you have opted in to connect to and with mobile applications that have received your permission before your device transmits any location information.

JiWire has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information.  The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software.  The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site ([www.jiwire.com](http://www.jiwire.com/)).

TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@jiwire.com](mailto:privacy@jiwire.com).  If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

  1. **Information Collection and Use**

We collect the following personal information from you

  * Contact Information such as name, email address, mailing address, phone number

We also collect the following information from you

  * Information about your business such as company name

We use this information to

  * Assess the needs of your business to determine suitable products
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Respond to customer service requests
  * Administer your account
  * Send you newsletters and marketing communications
  * Respond to your questions and concerns
  * Improve our Web site and marketing efforts
  * Conduct research and analysis

  1. **Information Sharing**

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement.  We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as sending email communications to you on our behalf. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

We may also disclose your personal information:

  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request,
  * if JiWire is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets,  you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information, 
  * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

  1. **User Access and Choice**

If your personally information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, or request the deletion/removal of it by contacting us via one of the methods listed below.  We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services.  We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

If you subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you.  Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or by contacting us via one of the methods listed below.

  1. **Tracking Technologies / Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time.

We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.  You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as contests or surveys, will be limited.

  * _Web Beacons / Gifs_

Our third party web analytics partners employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective.  Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users.  In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information.

  * _3 rd Parties_

The use of cookies by our partners is not covered by our privacy statement.  We do not have access or control over these cookies.  Our partners use session ID and persistent cookies for analytical purposes.

Our third party partners employ clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), images, and scripts that help them better manage content on our site. We do not tie the information gathered to our Customers’ or Users’ personally identifiable information.

  1. **Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us.  We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.  No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however.  Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

  1. **Additional Information**

  * _Links to 3 rd Party Sites_

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of JiWire. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any Web site you visit.

  * _Blog / Forum_

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. _To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us via one of the methods listed below._ In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

  * _Testimonials_

With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name.  If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us via one of the methods listed below. 

  * _Changes To This Policy_

We may change or update our privacy policy at our discretion. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you by posting a prominent announcement on our Site so that any changes are easy to find. We will obtain your consent before making any material changes to information we collect and the manner in which we use it. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

  1. **   Questions?**

If you have a question or issue with the JiWire Privacy Policy please send an email to [privacy@jiwire.com](mailto:privacy@jiwire.com) or you can send us a letter to: JiWire Inc., Attn: Privacy Policy Manager, 150 Post Street, Suite 500, San Francisco, CA, 94108.
